tombola.co.uk 2018-06-26

# Privacy Policy | tombola

As a “data controller” (meaning we are responsible for deciding what personal information we collect about you and what reasons we use it for) tombola (International) plc is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

Please read the following policy to understand how we collect and use information about users of our websites, tombola bingo [tombola.co.uk](https://www.tombola.co.uk/) and tombola arcade [www.tombolaarcade.co.uk](https://www.tombolaarcade.co.uk/) including versions of our websites viewed on mobile phones, tablets or other electronic devices (in all cases referred to as the ‘websites’).

The Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with the tombola Terms and Conditions and any additional applicable terms posted to the websites.

If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices, please contact us at [support@tombola.co.uk](mailto:support@tombola.co.uk) 

We collect information from you when you visit our website, use our app, deposit funds with us, play our games, contact us by telephone or email or receive a communication from us. The provision of information to us is voluntary; however, if you do not provide us with Transaction information or Preference information, we may not be able to provide our service or parts of it to you or provide you with updates

We hold this information on our servers securely in Ireland. Players can use the tombola bingo and arcade websites with the same login details.

We use the personal data we collect about you for various purposes. To do this we must rely on a specific “lawful bases” for processing that personal data. The tables below sets out under which basis we process different information about you, an explanation of the purpose of that processing and the specific rights in relation to your personal data, which may depend on the basis we process it for. 

You have certain legal rights, which are briefly summarised below, in relation to any personal data about you which we hold.

Where our processing of your personal data is based on your **consent** , you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. If you do decide to withdraw your consent we will stop processing your personal data for that purpose, unless there is another lawful basis we can rely on – in which case, we will let you know. Your withdrawal of your consent won’t impact any of our processing up to that point.

Where our processing of your personal data is necessary for our legitimate **interests** , you can object to this processing at any time. If you do this, we will need to show either a compelling reason why our processing should continue, which overrides your interests, rights and freedoms or that the processing is necessary for us to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim. 

If you have a question or concern about your privacy and rights on tombola, please do not hesitate to contact Us.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local supervisory authority. In the UK this is the Information Commissioner’s Office and more information can be found at <https://ico.org.uk/>.

Your personal data may be processed by us and/or our business partners, suppliers, sub-processing certain services on our behalf for the purposes specified above. For example, we share information with security verification companies, for the purpose of card/payment processing, identity and security checking (the Customer’s credit rating will be unaffected) or investigations on Tombola’s behalf. 

Such third parties have access to personal data solely for the purposes of performing the services specified in the applicable engagement, or to comply with applicable laws and not for any other purpose.

We will have in place an agreement with our service providers which will restrict how they are able to process your personal information and require them to keep it secure.

We may also use service providers in less direct ways, such as in the provision of our payment and finance systems, fraud verification. We may exchange information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of age verification, data cleansing, fraud protection, credit checks and/or risk reduction.

If you have been found to have defrauded or cheated the company or any service including game manipulation or payment fraud, including stolen credit cards, or fraudulent activity (including chargeback or other reversal of a payment) or money laundering, we reserve the right to share this information, including your identity with other online gaming websites, banks, credit companies and agencies.

Data privacy laws across the countries in the European Union, Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein, (the European Economic Area) are the same or very similar.  We have called this area ‘Europe’ for ease. If it is necessary for us to transfer your personal information outside Europe we will only make that transfer if we use a method approved as privacy-safe by the data privacy regulators in Europe: 

\- the country to which the personal information is to be transferred has been approved by them;

\- the recipient of the personal information is in the USA and has certified they will comply with the Privacy Shield rules to protect personal information, approved by them

\- the recipient of the personal information is legally bound to protect your personal information under binding corporate rules approved by them

\- we have made sure that there is a contract to protect your personal data with the recipient, using a template approved by them;

\- the transfer is needed for another reason approved by them, such as to make an international delivery of a prize at your request; or

\- where you explicitly consent to the transfer.

If any service provider is based outside of the European Economic Area, we will ensure that the provider is either a current subscriber to the EU/US Privacy Shield, or we have an appropriate contract for the international transfer of personal information with them. 

We may share any of your personal data with a prospective purchaser or purchaser of any part of our business, on the basis of our legitimate interests and the interests of our purchaser, so that they can appropriately value the business and assess any risks and continue doing business with you after the acquisition. 

In addition we may be required by law or by a court to disclose certain information about you or any engagement we may have with you to relevant regulatory, law enforcement and/or other competent authorities. We may also need to share your information in order to enforce or apply our legal rights under any agreed terms of business.

If you are our customer we will keep your personal data during the period your account remains active and then, after your account becomes inactive, for as long as is necessary in connection with both our and your legal rights and obligations. This may mean that we keep some types of personal data for longer than others.

We will only retain your personal data for a limited period of time. This will depend on a number of factors, including:

\- any laws or regulations that we are required to follow, especially regulatory requirements related to our online gambling licenses;

\- whether we are in a legal or other type of dispute with each other or any third party;

\- the type of information that we hold about you; and

\- whether we are asked by you or a regulatory authority to keep your personal data for a valid reason.

Any personal data contained in any work related correspondence or records may be retained for longer, dependant on the retention period of the file that your personal data is held on.

Access to your personal account information is restricted to you by your unique username and password. All details are stored under the strictest supervision. We want to ensure complete trust with our Players and to make playing tombola an enjoyable experience.

We have implemented suitable security policies and rules and fully understand the importance of information security and the need to store it correctly. We store all personal information within a secure network meaning data, passed back and forth between your computer and our systems is secured using a public key cryptography. Your computer exchanges key information with our servers to create a private conversation that only your computer and our servers can understand.

Our links with our payment gateways use technology to transmit any payment information securely. They in turn have secure encrypted links between themselves and all of the major banks to allow the payment to be processed. Tombola employees do NOT have access to your full credit/debit card details.

The services on tombola are not intended for or directed to persons under the age of 18. Any person who provides their information to us through our Websites represent that they are over 18. We reserve the right to access and verify any information submitted to us by you. If we become aware that a minor has attempted to or has submitted personal information via the Websites, we will take action to remove such information from our records.

You may opt out of receiving communications offering commercial goods or services at any time by adjusting your contact preferences within the “My Account” area of the websites, or by sending a request to [support@tombola.co.uk](mailto:support@tombola.co.uk) in accordance with our Privacy Policy. 

After 48 hours you will no longer receive any marketing via direct mail/email/SMS text. However, we may still need to correspond with you regarding account details, prize fulfilment and other operational matters and you consent to continue to receive these account communications even after you have opted-out of commercial offerings solicitations.

We reserve the right to update this privacy policy at any time but do not want to bother you about minor changes, so we will only provide you with a new privacy policy when we make any updates with a significant impact on your privacy which you should know about. The latest privacy policy with any other updates will always be available on our websites for you to check. We may also notify you in other ways from time to time about our use of your personal information.

Telphone: 0800 298 873

E-mail: [support@tombola.co.uk](mailto:support@tombola.co.uk)

Last updated on: 23 May 2018
